Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Nerv Headquarters - Test Facility 2
22 Days Ago
Commence activation.
Connecting main power to all circuits.
Main power supply connected.
Commencing activation system.
Activation voltage is approaching
critical level. 0.5, 0.2. Rising.
Begin the second phase
of the activation system.
Pilot has begun link-up.
Start system Phase 2.
Synapses inserted. Junctions connecting.
Transmitting pulse.
All circuits are operational.
No problems with initial contact.
Power supplied to brachial muscles
in both arms.
All nerve links checking out normal.
Check list satisfactory up to 2550.
Prepare for third stage connection.
Clear up to 2580.
Counting down to the absolute borderline.
0.9...
0.7...
0.5...
0.4...
0.3...
The pulses are flowing backward!
Something's going wrong in the third stage!
Rejection occurring in the
nerve center elements!
Cease contact! Break all circuits
through number six!
I can't! The signal's not being received!
Unit 00 is out of control!
Abort the experiment.
Shut off the power supply.
Yes, Sir!
Unit 00 has switched to backup power!
Thirty-five seconds until it comes
to a complete stop.
It's dangerous! Please get back!
Auto ejection activating!
No!
Complete shutdown in ten seconds. 9...
Use the special Bakelite! Hurry!
8...
7...
Rei!
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
Rei, are you all right?
Rei!
I see.
EPISODE FIVE
REI, BEYOND THE HEART
Rei Ayanami, age fourteen.
The first test subject chosen in
accordance with the Marduk Report.
The First Child.
She is the designated pilot for
Evangelion prototype Unit 00.
Her past has been eradicated. All her
personal records were erased.
So, what caused the accident during
the last experiment?
We still don't know.
However, we believe that mental instability
on the part of the pilot was a primary cause.
Mental instability? In Rei?
Yes, her mind became much more disturbed
than we had anticipated.
So what happened?
I don't know.
But could it be...
Did something occur to you?
No, that can't be it.
So this is our enemy.
I see. Most everything except the core
remains intact.
This is an ideal sample.
I appreciate it!
So, did you find anything new?
What the heck is this?
That's the code number for
"cannot be analyzed".
You mean, you don't know
what the heck it is?
Correct. We do know the Angel is
composed of a type of matter
characterized by both particulate and
wave properties, like light.
But you've at least found its power source,
haven't you?
Something like that anyway.
But we haven't been able to figure out
any of its operating principles.
Well, I guess there's still a whole world
of things we don't know about yet.
The world is filled with mysteries.
For example, take a look at this.
This is the Angel's inherent wave pattern.
What? Let me see.
Could this be...
Yes. Although they are composed
of a different form of matter,
their actual composition,
in terms of the arrangement
and spacing of the pattern, falls within
a 99.89% match of human genes.
99.89%?
It really shows us just how limited
our level of understanding is.
Bring it down... slowly...
It really shows us just how limited
our level of understanding is.
Okay!
It really shows us just how limited
our level of understanding is.
Okay!
That's good. Stop.
This is the core?
How's the rest of it?
It's pretty deteriorated. We can't expect
to use it as a reference.
That's not a problem.
Dispose of the remnants.
Yes, Sir.
What's wrong?
Well, nothing's wrong.
Are you aware that when you say
"nothing" that way,
it's the same as asking others
to pay attention to you?
Well, it's just that my father seems
to have burned his hands.
Burned?
I was just wondering how it happened.
Burns? Do you know?
It was before you arrived at Nerv.
Unit 00 went berserk during
the activation experiments.
You've heard about that, right?
Yes.
The pilot was trapped inside.
The pilot? You mean Ayanami, right?
It was Commander Ikari who rescued her.
He opened the super-heated hatch
with his bare hands.
My father did that?
That's how he burned his hands.
Go, Hideko!
Come on, lose!
You've got to treat us to pizza if you lose!
There, go for it!
You won't make it!
Now, let's sink a shot!
Oh my gosh! Those guys are looking at us!
Perverts!
Man, they've all got such incredible breasts.
Suzuhara's ogling us! Gross!
Hi, Shinji!
Hey, Chief!
What're you lookin' at so intently?
Nothing!
Was it Ayanami? Am I right?
No!
Oh, come on. That's suspicious...
Ayanami's boobs...
Ayanami's thighs...
Ayanami's...
...calves!
I told you, it's nothing like that.
Then, what were you looking at?
You can't fool me.
I was just wondering why she's always alone.
Come to think of it,
she hasn't had any friends since
she started here in the seventh grade.
There's just something about her that
makes her hard to approach.
She's probably just got a lousy personality.
You're both Eva pilots, right?
You should know her better than us.
He's right.
Well, I've hardly spoken to her.
Eva Unit 01 is now entering
the third stage cooling process.
Lower all systems to Phase 3 in Cage 6.
The earlier harmonics and
synchronization tests were good.
All numerical conditions
have been satisfied.
Roger. Transmit the results to Balthazar.
Roger.
Transmit the full range of the entry plug's
personal data to Melchior.
Data transmitting.
This is Melchior, roger. Circuits connected.
Initiating third stage cooling process.
CBL circulation has begun.
Condensation reactor,
commencing operation.
Vent waste fluid to the second
purification system.
The protein walls are in good condition.
No problems detected.
T minus 1,050 minutes until the Unit 00
re-activation experiment.
What is this?!
It's curry.
So you're still eating this instant stuff.
Look, you're a guest, so you've got
no right to complain.
What about you, Miss Misato?
For me...
Super Cup
Green Onion Roast Pork
Ta-da! Just pour it right in here!
Are you serious?
Oh, don't you know how good this is?
Okay...
Ordinary curry flavored instant ramen
can't compare to this!
Let's eat!
The trick is to put less hot water in the soup.
Misato cooked this, didn't she?
Yes.
Oh, can you tell?
Yes, by its taste.
How can she make something
ready-to-eat taste so awful?
Next time, invite me when
it's Shinji's turn to cook.
Shinji, you really ought to move out.
You shouldn't let one bad roommate
ruin your life.
I'm used to it now.
He's right, Ritsuko.
Never underestimate the ability
of the human animal
to adapt to its environment.
And anyway, if he does move...
Shinji, can you bring me
another one, please?
Right.
The red tape would be a pain.
He just got his permanent security card,
you know.
Oh, I almost forgot!
Shinji, would you do me a favor?
What is it?
Rei Ayanami's renewal card.
I keep forgetting to give this to her.
Would you mind delivering it
before you go to headquarters?
Sure.
What's the matter?
You're staring at Rei's picture.
Nothing!
Shinji, don't tell me...
No!
Oh, come on! You're blushing!
Well, you've got an official excuse
to go to Rei's place now.
This is your chance, isn't it?
Stop teasing me!
But I love teasing you.
You always take it so seriously!
Just like Misato.
I just find it strange that I know
so little about Ayanami,
even though we're both Eva pilots.
She's a very nice girl,
but she's like your father.
She's not very adept.
Not adept at what?
Living.
Ayanami
Excuse me?
Excuse me, it's Ikari.
I'm coming in, Ayanami!
Are these hers?
Well...
I didn't mean...
Do you mind moving?
I...
What is it?
Well, I mean, I was...
I was asked to, so...
What was it? The card, your card...
It's been renewed!
I was asked to deliver it.
So... So, I didn't mean
for any of this to happen.
Miss Ritsuko said she forgot to give it to you.
It's true. I rang your bell,
but there was no reply,
and the door was unlocked. So...
Central Dogma is currently
open to the public.
Group 3 should proceed directly
to the fourth gate.
This is your new card. Miss Ritsuko
asked me to deliver it to you.
I'm sorry about earlier.
About what?
You have a re-activation experiment
today, don't you?
Wouldn't it be great if it were
successful this time?
Say, aren't you afraid of getting in
Unit 00 again?
Why?
I heard that you were hurt pretty badly
in an earlier experiment,
so I was wondering if you were okay about it.
Aren't you Commander Ikari's son?
Yeah.
Don't you have faith in your
own father's work?
Of course not! How could I trust him?
What?
Rei, are you all right?
Rei...
The pilot was trapped inside.
It was Commander Ikari who rescued her.
He opened the super-heated hatch
with his bare hands.
That's how he burned his hands.
Rei.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
We will now commence the Unit 00
re-activation experiment.
First stage connection initiated.
Connecting main power supply.
Activation voltage has passed
the critical point.
Roger.
Shift format to Phase 2.
Connecting pilot to Unit 00.
Opening circuits.
Pulse and harmonics are normal.
No problems detected in synchronization.
All nerve links completed.
Central nervous system
elements are nominal.
Re-calculating, no error corrections.
Checklist is satisfactory up to 2590.
Approaching the absolute borderline.
2.5 more.
1.7...
1.2...
1.0...
0.8...
0.6...
0.5...
0.4...
0.3...
0.2...
0.1, and rising.
Borderline cleared.
Unit 00 has been activated.
Roger.
Beginning interlock test.
Ikari, an unidentified flying object
is approaching.
It is likely the fifth Angel.
Stop the test. All personnel,
alert status Level One.
You're not going to use Unit 00?
She's not ready to fight yet.
What's the status on Unit 01?
It'll be ready in 380 seconds.
Engage!
Yes, Sir.
Rei.
Re-activation was successful.
Return now.
The target is passing over Tonosawa.
Unit 01 is beginning launch preparations.
Releasing primary lock bolts.
Release confirmed.
Roger.
Releasing secondary restraints.
The target is now intruding into
Lake Ashino airspace.
Eva Unit 01 is ready for launch.
Launch!
We're detecting a high energy reaction
from inside the target!
What?!
The circumference area is accelerating!
It's converging!
It can't be!
No, dodge it!
Shinji!
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Shinji is saved, but his injuries
cause him to act spoiled.
Rei pushes him away.
Meanwhile, Misato tries to mount
a pin-point attack on the Angel.
Next Evangelion:
"Decisive Battle, New Tokyo-3"
DECISIVE BATTLE, NEW TOKYO-3